Lee Painton

Software Engineer

Contact

630 Wickenden Street Rear Upper Left Providence, RI 02903

(973) 978 7263

lee.painton@gmail.com facebook/lee.painton

Languages

C#, Java Python, SQL jQuery, Javascript CSS, HTML C++, VBScript

Technologies .Net, WPF

Winforms, Swing SQL Server

Summary

New graduate software developer with an interest in full stack development. Has experience in freelance software engineering in a practical setting. Has worked in a mission-critical teams and has hands-on experience in computer technology from hardware to software.

Education

May 2016 Masters in Computer Science

Brown University

GPA: 3.5

Master's project: https://github.com/Evangielis/BURLAP-BAG

May 2014 **B.S.** in Computer Science

Montclair State University

GPA: 3.9 – Summa Cum Laude

Experience

Software Development

2014-Now Freelance

Providence, RI

Software Engineer

Developed a Windows-based application suite for business client Metra. The suite includes Windows-based software tools to interface with the client's Axxess product line (http://axxessinterfaces.com/). The net benefit to the client was to modernize the software Metra offers its clients and thus increase the marketability of the company's products.

Information Technology

2010-2011 Celgene Corporation

Summit, NJ

Information Security Consultant

Worked with the Active Directory security team. Besides daily processing of tickets and documentation of business processes, also composed .NET scripts to automate the creation of directories, the assignment of security groups and the renewal of expiring accounts. This helped Celgene in its efforts to automate processes as part of the implementation of an ITIL compliant framework.

2007-2009 Becton Dickinson

Franklin Lakes, NJ

Information Security Analyst

Worked with a mission critical information security team to process security related tickets controlling access to servers and file systems. Also created software tools to integrate Lotus Notes with Active Directory and automate the monthly resetting of passwords on UNIX servers. Net benefit to employer was an increase in the efficiency of existing processes.

Projects

2015–2016 Metra App for Windowshttps://github.com/Evangielis/MetraApp

A commercial application to interface with Metra's line of Axxess radio mod boards. It was designed primarily with retailers in mind who might need to perform the same firmware updates and steering wheel control configurations multiple times a day.

2015 ConfusionQuiz https://github.com/Evangielis/ConfusionQuiz

This application interfaces with an Intel RealSense device and constructs both a video and an XML record of facial cues while the user takes a randomized quiz of designed to confuse them. Data was stored as a series of time-elapsed frames with recorded integer values for metrics offered by the Intel RealSense API.

2014-2015 Robocook https://github.com/h2r/robocook

A research tool in the form of a game about cooking with the help of a robot. This was written in JQuery utilizing elements of the GameQuery library. Uses WebSockets to communicate with an AI agent running BURLAP on a webserver and saves data on user actions. Was designed to support research being done by Stephanie Tellex's H2R group at Brown University. A demonstration can be found at http://elzar.cs.brown.edu/robocook/

The Assembler https://github.com/Evangielis/TheAssembler
Educational tool presented in the form of a game designed to teach concepts
of logic gates and assembly language to students. The final project consists of
three interlinked modules: a game environment, a logic gate simulator and a
fully functional terminal implementing a fully functional version of Madnik's

little man computer.